We wanted to define a character RNN with a two layer LSTM.
我们想要定义一个字符 RNN 它有两个 LSTM 层级
Here in my solution, I am running this code on
在我的答案中 我在 GPU 上运行代码
GPU and here's my code for defining our character level RNN.
下面说说我是如何定义字符级 RNN 的
First, I defined an LSTM layer, self.lstm.
首先定义一个 LSTM 层级 self.lstm
This takes in an input size,
第一个参数是输入大小
which is going to be the length of
该大小是独热编码的
a one-hot encoded input character and
输入字符的长度
that's just the length of all of my unique characters.
也就是所有唯一字符的长度
Then, it takes a hidden dimension a number of
后面的参数是隐藏维度
layers and a dropout probability that we've specified.
层级数量以及指定的丢弃概率
Remember that this will create a dropout layer in between multiple LSTM layers,
此参数将在多个 LSTM 层级之间创建丢弃层
and all of these are parameters that are going to be passed
在创建 RNN 时 会将所有这些参数
in as input to our RNN when it's constructed.
传入该 RNN 中
Then, I've set batch first to true because when we created our batch data,
将 batch_first 设为 True 因为在创建批次数据时
the first dimension is the batch size,
第一个维度是批次大小
rather than the sequence length.
而不是序列长度
Okay. Next, I've defined a dropout layer to go
Ok接下来 我在 LSTM 和最终线性层级之间
in-between my LSTM and a final linear layer.
定义了丢弃层
Then, I have FC, my final fully connected linear layer.
接着是 fc 即最终全连接线性层级
This takes in our LSTM outputs,
它的参数是 LSTM 输入
which are going to be dimension and hidden.
维度是 n_hidden
It's going to output our character class scores for the most likely next character.
输出最有可能的下个字符的字符类别分数
So, these are the class scores for each possible next character.
这些是每个潜在下个字符的类别分数
This output size is the same size as our input,
这个输出大小和输入大小一样
the length of our character vocabulary.
即字符词汇表的长度
Then, I move to the forward function.
然后是 forward 函数
I'm passing my input X and a hidden state to my LSTM layer here.
向这里的 LSTM 层级传入输入 x 和隐藏状态
This produces my LSTM output and a new hidden state.
生成 LSTM 输出和新的隐藏状态
I'm going to pass the LSTM output through
将 LSTM 输出
the dropout layer that I defined here to get a new output.
传入在这里定义的丢弃层并获得新的输出
Then, I'm making sure to reshape this output,
然后变形此输出
so that the last dimension is our hidden dim.
使最后一个维度是隐藏维度
This negative one basically means I'm going to be stacking up the outputs of the LSTM.
这个 -1 表示我将堆叠 LSTM 的输出
Finally, I'm passing this V-shaped output to the final fully connected layer.
最后 将这个变形后的输出传入最终全连接层
Then, I'm returning this final output and
然后返回此最终输出
the hidden state that was generated by our LSTM.
以及 LSTM 生成的隐藏状态
These two functions in addition to the init hidden function complete my model.
这两个函数以及 init_hidden 函数构成了我的模型
Next, it's time to train and let's take a look at the training loop that was provided.
接下来训练模型 我们看看提供的训练循环
This function takes in a model to train some data,
这个函数的参数是要训练的模型、数据
and the number of epics to train for,
训练周期数
and a batch size,
以及批次大小
and sequence length that define our mini batch size.
和定义迷你批次大小的序列长度
It also takes in a few more training parameters.
还有其他几个训练参数
First in here, I've defined my optimizer and my loss function.
首先在这里定义优化器和损失函数
The optimizer is a standard Adam optimizer with
优化器是标准 Adam 优化器
a learning rate set to the past and learning rate up here.
学习速率设为在这里传入的学习速率
The last function is cross entropy loss,
最后一个函数是交叉熵损失
which is useful for when we're outputting character class scores.
用于输出字符类别分数
Here, you'll see some details about creating
这部分代码用于创建验证数据
some validation data and moving our model to GPU if it's available.
并将模型移到 GPU 上（如果有）
Here, you can see the start of our epic loop.
这是周期循环的开头
At the start of each epic,
在每个周期开始时
I'm initializing the hidden state of our LSTM.
我将初始化 LSTM 的隐藏状态
Recall that this takes in the batch size of our data to define the size of
参数是数据的批次大小 用于定义隐藏状态的大小
the hidden state and it returns a hidden in cell state that are all zeros.
返回全为 0 的隐藏单元状态
Then, inside this epic loop,
在此周期循环里
I have my batch loop.
是批次循环
This is getting our X and Y mini batches from our get batches generator.
从 get_batches 生成器中获取 x y 迷你批次
Remember that this function basically iterates through are encoded data,
此函数会遍历编码数据
and returns batches of inputs X and targets
并返回批次输入 x 和目标 y
Y. I'm then converting the input into a one-hot encoded representation,
然后将输入转换为独热编码表示法
and I'm converting both X and Y are
将输入 x 和目标 y 转换为
inputs and targets into Tensors that can be seen by our model.
能够传入模型中的张量
If GPU's available, I'm moving those inputs and targets to our GPU device.
如果有 GPU 则将这些输入和目标转移到 GPU 设备上
The next thing that you see is making sure that we detach
下一步是确保将传入的隐藏状态
any past in hidden state from its history.
与其历史记录分离
Recall that the hidden state of an LSTM layer is a Tuple,
LSTM 层级的隐藏状态是一个元组
and so here, we are getting the data as a tuple.
所以这里的数据是元组
Then, we proceed with back propagation as usual.
然后执行反向传播
We zero out any accumulated gradients and pass in our input Tensors to our model.
清零积累的梯度并将输入张量传入模型中
We also pass in the latest hidden state here.
并且在这里传入最新的隐藏状态
In this returns of final output and a new hidden state,
返回最终输出和新的隐藏状态
then we calculate the loss by looking at the predicted output and the targets.
然后通过查看预测输出和目标来计算损失
Recall that in the forward function of our model,
在模型的 forward 函数中
I smashed the batch size and sequence length of our LSTM outputs into one dimension,
我将 LSTM 输出的批次大小和序列长度变成了一个维度
and so I'm doing the same thing for our targets here.
在这里也针对目标执行相同的处理流程
Then, we're performing back propagation and moving
然后进行反向传播
one step in the right direction updating the weights of our network.
朝着右侧方向移动一个步长并更新网络权重
Now before the optimization step,
在优化步骤之前
I've added one line of code that may look unfamiliar.
我添加了一行新的代码
I'm calling clip grad norm.
即调用 clip_grad_norm_
Now, this kind of LSTM model has one main problem with gradients.
这种 LSTM 模型在梯度方面有一个主要问题
They can explode and get really, really big.
梯度可能会爆炸并变得非常非常大
So, what we do is we can clip the gradients,
因此我们可以截断梯度
we just set some clip threshold,
设置一个截断阈值
and then if the gradient is larger than that threshold,
如果梯度大于该阈值
we set it to that clip threshold,
则将梯度设为该截断阈值
and encode we do this by just passing in
在这里 我们只需传入参数
the parameters and the value that we want to clip the gradients at.
以及梯度截断阈值
In this case, this value is passed in,
我们已经在 train 函数中
in our train function as a value five.
传入这个值 值为 5
Okay. So, we take a backwards step,
执行反向传播步骤后
then we clip our gradients,
截断梯度
and we perform an optimization step.
执行优化步骤
At the end here, I'm doing something very similar for processing
最后对验证数据执行很相似的流程
our validation data except not performing the back propagation step.
但是不执行反向传播步骤
Then, I'm printing out some statistics about our loss.
然后输出损失值
Now with this train function defined,
定义好 train 函数后
I can go about instantiating and training a model.
实例化并训练模型
In the exercise notebook,
在练习 notebook 中
I've left these hyper parameters for you to define.
你需要定义这些超参数
I've set our hidden dimension to the value of 512 and a number of layers up two,
我将隐藏维度设为 512
which we talked about before.
并将层数设为 2
Then, I have instantiated our model, and printed it out,
然后实例化模型并输出该模型
and we can see that we have 83 unique characters as input,
可以看出输入有 83 个唯一字符
512 as a hidden dimension,
隐藏维度是 512
and two layers in our LSTM.
有两个 LSTM 层级
For a dropout layer,
对于丢弃层
we have the default dropout value of 0.5 and for our last fully connected layer,
默认丢弃概率是 0.5 对于最终全连接层
we have our Input features,
参数包括输入特征数
which is the same as this hidden dimension and our output features,
它和这个隐藏维度一样 然后是输出特征数
the number of characters.
等于字符数
Then, there are more hyper parameters that define
其他超参数包括
our batch size sequence length and number of epics to train for.
批次大小、序列长度和训练周期数
Here, I've set the sequence length to 100,
我将序列长度设为 100
which is a lot of characters,
包含很多字符
but it gives our model a great deal of context to learn from.
但是为模型提供了大量上下文信息
I also want to note that the hidden dimension is
注意 隐藏维度是
basically the number of features that your model can detect.
模型能够检测的特征数量
Larger values basically allow a network to learn more text features.
更大的值使网络能够学习更多文本特征
There's some more information below in this notebook about defining hyper parameters.
下面还有更多定义超参数的信息
In general, I'll try to start out with a pretty big model like this,
通常 我会先建立这样的大型模型
multiple LSTM layers and a large hidden dimension.
有多个 LSTM 层级和很大的隐藏维度
Then, I'll basically take a look at the loss as
然后看看模型的训练损失
this model trains and if it's decreasing, I'll keep going.
如果损失降低了 则继续
But if it's not decreasing as I expect,
如果不像预期得那样降低
then I'll probably change some hyper parameters.
则更改某些超参数
Our text data is pretty large and here,
我们的文本数据很庞大
I've trained our entire model for 20 epics on GPU.
我在 GPU 上训练整个模型 20 个周期
I can see the training and validation loss over time decreasing.
可以看到训练和验证损失逐渐降低了
Around epic 15, I'm seeing the lost slow down a bit.
在第 15 个周期左右 看到损失降低速度变慢了
But it actually looks like the validation and
但是即使在第 20 个周期之后
training loss are still decreasing even after epic 20.
验证和训练损失还在降低
I could have stood to train for an even longer amount of time.
还可以训练更长时间
I encourage you to read this information about setting
这部分是关于如何设置模型超参数
the hyper parameters of a model and really getting the best model.
以及获得最佳模型的信息 建议阅读一下
Then, after you've trained a model like I've just done,
然后 像我这样训练模型之后
you can save it by name and then there's one last step,
你可以保存模型并设定名称
which is using that model to make predictions and generate some new text,
最后还有一步 使用模型做出预测并生成一些新的文本
which I'll go over next.
接下来我将讲解这方面的知识